{
    "id": "a95cfbe209114bd482d530c09c4b4495",
    "title": "Reported Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He asked me what ……………………….. doing there.",
            "description": "In reported questions the subject goes before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was I",
                "I was"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "64c779d047904cf5a49f5e78ab91a487"
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ………………………….. his examination.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "has passed",
                "had passed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e11fd8bff4f746afb32b2a7e4930a0a7"
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ……………………… unwell.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d7ae0e9a6b404a128e441f3ac2522b8d"
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy said that he ………………………… then.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "slept",
                "was sleeping",
                "is sleeping"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a60c9864741a4cb2a6ac1060fe29cae0"
        },
        {
            "question": "The stranger asked where ……………………",
            "description": "Do is not used in reported questions.",
            "answers": [
                "l live",
                "I lived",
                "did I live"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ef5a1d008963400d8331f71dbebd713d"
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor said that the patient ……………………… in the night.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "has died",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2d8e282ee36a457eb2915410b195b45a"
        },
        {
            "question": "The girl exclaimed that she …………………….. very clever.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "is",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e37a21c371a742289e77e83aa4d974d8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wrote that I ………………………… him next day.",
            "description": "Would is the past tense of will in direct speech. When we convert this into direct speech, we get: He wrote, ‘I will visit you tomorrow.’",
            "answers": [
                "visited",
                "will visit",
                "would visit"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4b6eb46fef9f476c957be23671866d47"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me …………………………. I knew his name.",
            "description": "We use if or whether to report questions.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "80d181985e52477fbaba372b718e46f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked the girl if she ……………………… me her pen.",
            "description": "I asked the girl, 'Will you lend me your pen?' When we convert this into indirect speech we get: I asked the girl whether she would lend me her pen. ",
            "answers": [
                "will lend",
                "would lend",
                "lent"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ca08f4b1a6c54be3aac98c73ba6d6d64"
        },
        {
            "question": "He told us that he ………………………. for an hour.",
            "description": "He told us, 'I have waited for an hour.' When we convert this into indirect speech we get: He told us that he had waited for an hour. ",
            "answers": [
                "has waited",
                "had waited"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "838d1f572984404faeac9ffcdefdc42b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The speaker said that it …………………… him great pleasure to be there that evening.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the reported speech will also be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "gives",
                "has given",
                "gave"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "94013ddf2006443fbd10b94e1a35138f"
        }
    ]
}